<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>xyz.rescribe.rescribe</id>
  
  <name>Rescribe</name>
  <developer_name>Rescribe Ltd</developer_name>
  <summary>OCR images, PDFs and Google Books</summary>
  
  <description><p>An easy-to-use desktop tool to recognise and extract text from images, PDFs and Google Books. It uses the Tesseract OCR engine, combined with modern and efficient preprocessing and analysis pipelines, to produce high quality output in plain text, hOCR and searchable PDF format. The tool has been built with a focus on OCR of historical printed works, but it includes modern language options and also works well on modern printed works.</p></description>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Main window</caption>
      <image>https://rescribe.xyz/rescribe/screenshot-03.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Dark mode</caption>
      <image>https://rescribe.xyz/rescribe/screenshot-04.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>OCR in progress</caption>
      <image>https://rescribe.xyz/rescribe/screenshot-05.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>OCR completed</caption>
      <image>https://rescribe.xyz/rescribe/screenshot-06.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <url type="homepage">https://rescribe.xyz/rescribe</url>

  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0</project_license>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">xyz.rescribe.rescribe.desktop</launchable>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#cdab8f</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#63452c</color>
  </branding>

  <releases>
    <release version="1.4.0" date="2025-12-02" type="stable">
      <description>
        <p>Ensure directories of PNGs are always binarised (thanks Alex Turton), updated GUI library, updated flatpak version to use xdg desktop portals for sandboxed file access.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.3.0" date="2024-04-10" type="stable">
      <description>
        <p>Added support for PDFs with embedded rotated images, created new icon, added version number to MacOS and Windows builds, fixed possible crash on Windows caused by temporary jpegs not being closed before removal, fixed issue where an invalid PDF could be created in some cases, fixed issue with flatpak where not all trainings were available.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.2.0" date="2024-02-16" type="stable">
      <description>
        <p>Fixed bug with directories containing files with spaces causing the process to fail, added concatenated text output named bookname.txt, fixed selecting a custom training in flatpak build, fixed getgbook on arm64 MacOS, improved layout of log area to fill all available space in the window, improved readability of log area text.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.0" date="2023-02-13" type="stable">
      <description>
        <p>Improved PDF reading by adding support for embedded CCITT images. Improved PDF parsing to prevent a possible crash with bad PDF files. Improved error messages for unreadable PDFs. Improved GUI theme thanks to an update to Fyne.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.0" date="2022-03-22" type="stable">
      <description>
        <p>Thanks to our fabulous Kickstarter backers, lots of improvements! Added GUI, added PDF extractor, added Google Book downloader, created a single binary for OSX for M1 and amd64, added file renamer so page files no longer need a particular naming format, added option to disable page wiping, added option to create full size PDF.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

</component>
